私人博客
约翰·H·华生医生
你已登录为J·H·华生
夏 洛 克
本尼迪克特·康伯巴奇
马丁·弗里曼
翻译、制作、特效：goodliuwu
根据阿瑟·柯南·道尔爵士作品改编
10月12日
11月26日
1月27日
粉红的研究
错了！
你知道去哪里
找我，
夏·福
（位于伦敦肉市场  全称圣巴塞洛缪医院）
信息
- 已收
- 已发
如果兄弟有绿色梯子
就逮捕兄弟，
夏·福
夏
洛
克
·
福
尔
摩
斯
威斯敏斯特城区
贝克街
雷斯垂德探长  负责调查
自杀邪典
海瑞·华生
克拉拉赠
瑞  琪
左撇子
瑞琪
德文
[名词]
复
仇
瑞
琪
儿
[人名]
潮湿
干燥
干净
脏
已婚
不幸福
10+
年
干净
脏
经 常
摘 下
一系列情夫
英国天气
地图
本地
预告
未来24小时
七天预报
【地图】
本地
预告
未来24小时
七天预报
地图
阿波罗13号的名言：休斯顿，我们有麻烦了
布里克斯顿 053
布里克斯顿 002
布里克斯顿 047
布里克斯顿 051
布里克斯顿 053
布里克斯顿 002
布里克斯顿 047
布里克斯顿 051
贝克街，
速回
如果方便的话，
夏·福
如不方便，
亦请速回，
夏·福
可能有危险，
在
劳
瑞
斯
顿
花
园
发
生
什
么
事
了
？
我
一
定
是
在劳瑞斯顿花园
发生什么事了？
我
一
定
昏
过
去
了
在劳瑞斯顿花园
发生什么事了？
我一定昏过去了
诺
森
伯
兰
街
号
请
过
来
未知来电
反社会人格  伦理道德缺失  缺乏正常情感
我的手机网
找到我的手机
请从旁边面板选择操作，或使用下面的快捷方式
你的手机将在3分钟内定位
伦敦 出租司机
跟我来
日本的神风敢死队 自杀式袭击
快死了
你的博客怎么样？
How's your blog going?
对，好，很好
Yeah, good. Very good.
你一个字都没写吧？
You haven't written a word, have you?
你刚写了“依然存在信任问题”
You just wrote "Still has trust issues".
而你在倒读我写的字
And you read my writing upside down.
明白我的意思吗？
You see what I mean?
约翰
John
你是个军人
you're a soldier,
你需要一段时间才能调整到平民生活
and it's going to take you a while to adjust to civilian life,
把你遭遇的每一件事情写进博客
and writing a blog about everything that happens to you
会实实在在帮到你
will honestly help you.
我什么事都没遇到
Nothing happens to me.
你说没有红色车是什么意思？
What do you mean, there's no ruddy car?
他开车去了滑铁卢，对不起
He went to Waterloo, I'm sorry.
- 叫辆出租车  - 我从来不打车
- Get a cab! - I never get cabs!
- 我爱你  - 何时？
- I love you. - When?
叫辆出租车
Get a cab!
我的丈夫
My husband...
生前快乐幸福，生活美满
was a happy man who lived life to the full.
他热爱他的家庭和工作
He loved his family and his work,
却选择了这种方式结束生命
and that he should have taken his own life in this way
这是个谜
is a mystery
也是震惊，对于所有熟识他的人
and a shock to all who knew him.
好，好，出租！
Yes, yes! Taxi!
- 我要回去两分钟，伙计  - 怎么
- I'll be back in two minutes, mate. - What?
- 我得回家拿伞  - 你可以和我一起打
- I'm just going home to get my umbrella. - You can share mine.
就两分钟  行吧
Two minutes, all right?
18岁青年   在体育中心内自杀
她还在跳舞吗
She still dancing?
对  要是这也算跳舞
Yeah, if you can call it that.
- 拿了她的车钥匙吗  - 从她包里拿了
- Did you get the car keys off her? - Got them out of her bag.
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
交通次大臣贝丝·达文波的尸体
The body of Beth Davenport, Junior Minister for Transport,
于昨天后半夜  在大伦敦一座建筑工地被发现
was found late last night on a building site in Greater London.
初步调查显示为自杀
Preliminary investigations suggest that this was suicide.
我们可以确认  这起明显的自杀案件相当近似于
We can confirm that this apparent suicide closely resembles those
杰弗里·帕特森爵士和詹姆斯·菲利莫的案子
of SirJeffrey Patterson and James Phillimore.
有鉴于此，这些事件现在被认为存在关联
In the light of this, these incidents are now being treated as linked.
调查已经展开
The investigation is ongoing,
不过雷斯垂德探长会在现在回答问题
but Detective Inspector Lestrade will take questions now.
探长，自杀怎么会有关联？
Detective Inspector, how can suicides be linked?
这个嘛，他们都服了相同的毒药
Well, they all took the same poison.
他们都被发现于没有理由出现的地方
They were all found in places they had no reason to be.
他们中没人出现过先期征兆
None of them had shown any prior indication.
但是你不能连环自杀啊
But you can't have serial suicides.
显然是可以的
Well, apparently you can.
这三个人，他们没有什么关联吗？
These three people, there's nothing that links them?
我们还没有发现关联，但是
There's no link we've found yet, but
我们还在寻找 肯定有关联
we're looking for it - there has to be one.
要是你们都收到短信，请无视它
If you've all got texts, please ignore them.
上面就写着“错了”
It just says "Wrong".
对，不过无视就好
Yeah. Well, just ignore that.
要是没有其它问题给雷斯垂德探长
If there are no more questions for Detective Inspector Lestrade,
这次记者招待会就到此为止
I'm going to bring this session to an end.
如果这是自杀案件  你们又在调查什么
If they're suicides, what are you investigating?
如我所说  这些自杀案件显然有所关联
As I say, these suicides are clearly linked.
这是一次不同寻常的情况
It's an unusual situation.
我们已有最好的人员在调查
We've got our best people investigating.
又是"错了"
Says "Wrong" Again.
再回答一个问题
One more question.
有没有一点可能性这是谋杀呢？
Is there any chance that these are murders?
如果是的话  会不会是连环杀手？
And if they are, is this the work of a serial killer?
我…我知道你们喜欢写这些
I know that you like writing about these,
但这些确实显示为自杀
but these do appear to be suicides.
我们知道区别，毒药显然是自己吞下的
We know the difference. The poison was clearly self-administered.
对，但如果他们是被谋杀，大家怎么才能保障自己安全
Yes, but if they are murders, how do people keep themselves safe?
哦，不要去自杀
Well, don't commit suicide.
《每日邮报》
DailyMail.
显然，这对大家来说是恐慌时刻
Obviously, this is a frightening time for people,
但大家要做的，就是采取合理的预防措施
but all anyone has to do is exercise reasonable precautions.
我们就都能如愿保障安全
We are all as safe as we want to be.
谢谢
Thank you.
你必须阻止他这么胡闹
You've got to stop him doing that.
他搞得我们像傻瓜
He's making us look like idiots.
要是你告诉我他怎么办到的 我会阻止他
If you can tell me how he does it, I'll stop him.
约翰
John!
约翰·华生
John Watson!
斯坦福，迈克·斯坦福，我们以前在巴茨医院共事
Stamford, Mike Stamford. We were at Barts together.
对，抱歉，迈克，你好
Yes, sorry, yes, Mike, hello.
- 没事，我理解，我胖了，  - 没有
- Yeah, I know, I got fat. - No, no.
我听说你到国外什么地方挨枪子儿去了，怎么回事？
I heard you were abroad somewhere getting shot at. What happened?
我中了枪
I got shot.
那你还在巴茨医院吗
Are you still at Barts, then?
现在教书  阳光小青年，跟我们以前一样
Teaching now, yeah. Bright young things like we used to be.
老天  我讨厌他们
God, I hate them.
你呢？工作安顿之前，先住在城里吗？
What about you? Just staying in town till you get yourself sorted?
靠军队退休金没法在伦敦过日子
I can't afford London on an Army pension.
你就是住其它地方也不行
You couldn't bear to be anywhere else.
那不是我认识的约翰·华生
That's not the John Watson I know.
对，我不是那个约翰·华生了
Yeah, I'm not the John Watson...
海瑞没帮上忙吗
Couldn't Harry help?
切，好像还有指望似的
Yeah, like that's going to happen
我不知道，找人合租之类呢？
I don't know, get a flatshare or something?
得了，谁愿意当我的室友？
Come on, who'd want me for a flatmate?
怎么了
What?
你是今天第二个跟我说这话的人
You're the second person to say that to me today.
第一个是谁？
Who was the first?
有多新鲜
How fresh?
刚刚送来  67岁  自然死亡
Just in. 67, natural causes.
以前在这工作，我认识他，人很好
Used to work here. I knew him, he was nice.
好
Fine.
我们先从短马鞭开始
We'll start with the riding crop.
今天不太顺，是吧
So, bad day, was it?
我要知道20分钟后的瘀伤形状
I need to know what bruises form in the next 20 minutes.
一个人的不在场证明就靠它了  发短信给我
A man's alibi depends on it. Text me.
那个，我想问一下，也许等你工作完后…
Listen, I was wondering. Maybe later, when you're finished...
你涂了唇膏，你刚才没涂唇膏啊
You're wearing lipstick. You weren't wearing lipstick before.
我...我稍微润色了一下
I, er... I refreshed it a bit.
不好意思，你刚才是说？
Sorry, you were saying?
我是想问 你想喝咖啡吗
I was wondering if you'd like to have coffee.
清咖啡，两块糖，麻烦了，我就在楼上
Black, two sugars, please. I'll be upstairs.
好吧
Ok.
- 跟我那会儿有点不一样了  - 你都想不到
- Bit different from my day. - You've no idea!
迈克，能否借用你的电话，我的没信号
Mike, can I borrow your phone? There's no signal on mine.
- 固定电话有问题吗  - 我更喜欢发短信
- And what's wrong with the landline? - I prefer to text.
抱歉，在我大衣里
Sorry, it's in my coat.
哦，给，用我的吧
Er, here...use mine.
哦，谢谢
Oh, thank you.
这是我的一个老朋友，约翰·华生
This is an old friend of mine, John Watson.
阿富汗还是伊拉克？
Afghanistan or Iraq?
- 什么？  - 哪一个，阿富汗还是伊拉克？
- Sorry? - Which was it, in Afghanistan or Iraq?
阿富汗，不好意思，你怎么…
Afghanistan. Sorry, how did you...?
啊茉莉，咖啡，谢谢你
Ah, Molly, coffee, thank you.
你的唇膏怎么没了
What happened to the lipstick?
我用着没效果
It wasn't working for me.
真的？我倒觉得很有改善
Really? I thought it was a big improvement.
你的嘴现在看着太小
Your mouth's too small now.
好吧
Ok.
你对小提琴有何看法？
How do you feel about the violin?
抱歉，什么？
I'm sorry, what?
我在思考问题时会拉小提琴
I play the violin when I'm thinking
有时我会一连几天不说话
and sometimes I don't talk for days on end.
会让你心烦吗？
Would that bother you?
未来的室友应该彼此了解最坏的一面
Potential flatmates should know the worst about each other.
- 你…你和他说起过我吗  - 一个字也没有
- You told him about me? - Not a word.
那谁说过室友的事了？
Then who said anything about flatmates?
我说过，早上告诉迈克，我这人肯定很难找到室友
I did. Told Mike this morning I must be a difficult man to find a flatmate for.
现在他来了，刚过午餐
Now here he is, just after lunch,
带来一个老友，显然刚在阿富汗服完兵役回家
with an old friend clearly just home from military service in Afghanistan.
这不难推论
Wasn't a difficult leap.
你怎么知道阿富汗的事
How did you know about Afghanistan?
我看中一处不错的小地方 在伦敦市中心
Got my eye on a nice little place in central London.
我们应该有能力负担
We ought to be able to afford it.
我们明天晚上在那里见，七点
We'll meet there tomorrow evening, seven o'clock.
抱歉  赶时间
Sorry, got to dash.
我想我把短马鞭忘在停尸间了
I think I left my riding crop in the mortuary.
就这样吗？
Is that it?
什么就这样？
Is that what?
我们才刚见面  就要一起去看房了吗
We've only just met and we're going to go and look at a flat?
有问题吗
Problem?
我们一点也不了解对方
We don't know a thing about each other.
我不知道我们去哪里见
I don't know where we're meeting.
我甚至不知道你的名字
I don't even know your name.
我知道你是个军医
I know you're an Army doctor
刚从阿富汗因伤退役回来
and you've been invalided home from Afghanistan.
我知道你有个兄弟担心你
I know you've got a brother worried about you,
但你不向他求助
but you won't go to him for help
因为你看不惯他
because you don't approve of him,
可能因为他是酒鬼
possibly because he's an alcoholic,
更可能是因为他最近抛弃了自己的妻子
more likely because he recently walked out on his wife.
而且我知道  你的咨询师认为…
And I know your therapist thinks
你的跛腿是心理疾病，相当准确，我觉得
your limp's psychosomatic, quite correctly, I'm afraid.
这样应该可以继续下去了吧，你觉得呢？
That's enough to be going on with, don't you think?
名字是夏洛克·福尔摩斯
The name's Sherlock Holmes,
那地址是贝克街221B
and the address is 221 B Baker Street.
午安
Afternoon.
对，他总这样
Ya, he's always like that.
你好
Hello.
- 福尔摩斯先生  - 叫夏洛克就好
- Ah, Mr Holmes. - Sherlock, please.
这儿是主城区，肯定很贵吧
Well, this is a prime spot. Must be expensive.
哈德森太太，就是房东，给我特惠价
Mrs Hudson, the landlady, she's given me a special deal.
欠我个人情，几年前
Owes me a favour. A few years back,
她丈夫在弗罗里达被判死刑
her husband got himself sentenced to death in Florida.
我帮了一下
I was able to help out.
抱歉，你阻止了她丈夫受刑？
Sorry, you stopped her husband being executed?
不，我确保了行刑
Oh, no, I ensured it.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
哈德森太太  这位是约翰·华生医生
Mrs Hudson, DrJohn Watson.
- 你好 请进吧   - 谢谢
- Hello. Come in. - Thank you.
我们走吧
Shall we...?
可以弄得很好
Well, this could be very nice.
的确很好
Very nice indeed.
是的
Yes.
是的，我也这么想，我的想法一样
Yes, I think so, my thoughts precisely.
- 所以我就直接搬进来了 - 只要清掉这些垃圾
-So I went straight ahead and moved in.-Soon as we get this rubbish cleaned up.
- 那这都是...  - 哦，显然我可以收拾下
-So this is all... -Well, obviously I can straighten things up
稍微的
a bit.
- 那是颗骷髅  - 我的一个朋友
- That's a skull. - Friend of mine.
我说朋友...
When I say friend...
你觉得如何，华生医生？
What do you think, then, Dr Watson?
楼上还有间卧室，如果你们需要两间卧室的话
There's another bedroom upstairs, if you'll be needing two bedrooms.
我们当然需要两间
Of course we'll be needing two.
哦，别担心，这里各种人都有
Oh, don't worry, there's all sorts round here.
隔壁特纳太太家有一对结婚了的
Mrs Turner next door's got married ones.
夏洛克  看你弄这么乱
Oh...Sherlock! The mess you've made.
昨晚我在网上搜了下你
I looked you up on the internet last night.
有什么有意思的吗？
Anything interesting?
找到了你的网站  "演绎学"
Found your website. The Science Of Deduction.
你怎么想？
What did you think?
你说你能通过领带识别一名软件工程师
You said you could identify a software designer by his tie
通过左手大拇指识别民航飞行员
and an airline pilot by his left thumb?
是的
Yes.
我还能通过你的脸和腿  看出你的军人职业
And I can read your military career in your face and your leg,
通过你的手机  知道你哥的饮酒习惯
and your brother's drinking habits in your mobile phone.
怎么办到的？
How?
这些自杀案怎么样，夏洛克？
What about these suicides, then, Sherlock?
我觉得这正是你拿手的
I thought that'd be right up your street.
三起完全一样
Three exactly the same.
四起
Four.
有第四起了，而且这次有些不同
There's been a fourth. And there's something different this time.
第四起？
A fourth?
- 哪里？  - 布里克斯顿的劳瑞斯顿花园
- Where? - Brixton, Lauriston Gardens.
这次有什么新情况？不然你不会来找我
What's new about this one? You wouldn't have come to me if there wasn't something differente.
- 你知道他们从未有留言吧？  - 对
- You know how they never leave notes? - Yes.
这次有
This one did.
你来吗？
Will you come?
- 谁是法医？  - 安德森
- Who's on forensics? - Anderson.
他跟我合不来
He doesn't work well with me.
- 他又不会当你助手  - 我需要一个助手
- Well, he won't be your assistant. - I need an assistant.
- 你来吗？  - 不坐警车，我就跟在后面
- Will you come? - Not in a police car, I'll be right behind.
谢谢
Thank you.
太棒了！耶！
Brilliant! Yes!
四起连环自杀案件  现在还有留言
Four serial suicides and now a note.
哦，过圣诞了
Oh, it's Christmas.
哈德森太太  我会晚归  可能需要点吃的
Mrs Hudson, I'll be late. Might need some food.
我是你房东，亲爱的，不是管家
I'm your landlady, dear, not your housekeeper.
冷的食物就行，约翰
Something cold will do. John,
来杯茶，跟在家里一样
have a cup of tea, make yourself at home.
不用等我
Don't wait up!
看看他，劲头十足...
Look at him, dashing about...
我丈夫以前也一样
My husband was just the same.
但你更属于坐得住的类型，我看得出来
But you're more the sitting-down type, I can tell.
我来帮你沏茶  你歇歇腿
I'll make you that cuppa, you rest your leg.
该死的腿！抱歉，我非常抱歉
Damn my leg! Sorry, I'm so sorry.
只是有时这该死的东西…
It's just sometimes this bloody thing...
我理解，亲爱的，我臀部也是
I understand, dear, I've got a hip.
来杯茶就太好了，谢谢
Cup of tea'd be lovely. Thank you.
就这一次，亲爱的  我不是你管家
Just this once, dear, I'm not your housekeeper.
- 再来几片饼干，如果有的话   - 不是你管家哦
- Couple of biscuits too, if you've got 'em. - Not your housekeeper!
你是个医生
You're a doctor.
实际上，你是一名军医
In fact, you're an Army doctor.
是的
Yes.
做得好吗？
Any good?
非常好
Very good.
见过无数创伤，是吧，致命的伤
Seen a lot of injuries, then. Violent deaths.
呃，是啊
Well, yes.
有点困扰，我打赌？
Bit of trouble too, I bet?
当然，是的，这辈子看够了，太多了
Of course. Yes. Enough for a lifetime, far too much.
- 还想看更多吗  - 哦，老天，当然
- Want to see some more? - Oh, God, yes.
抱歉，哈德森太太，不喝茶了  要出去
Sorry, Mrs Hudson, I'll skip the tea. Off out.
你俩都去？
Both of you?
不可能的自杀案件？四起？
Impossible suicides? Four of them?
没理由坐在家里，终于有好玩的了
No point sitting at home when there's finally something fun going on!
- 看看你，满心欢喜，这不得体  - 管他得不得体
- Look at you, all happy. It's not decent. - Who cares about decent?
游戏，哈德森太太，开始了
The game, Mrs Hudson, is on!
出租车
Taxi!
好吧，你有一些问题…
OK, you've got questions...
对，我们要去哪儿？
Yeah, where are we going?
犯罪现场，下一个？
Crime scene. Next?
- 你是谁？做什么的？  - 你觉得呢？
- Who are you? What do you do? - What do you think?
- 我本想说...私家侦探  - 但是...
- I'd say...private detective. - But...?
但警察不会找私家侦探
But the police don't go to private detectives.
我是个“咨询侦探”
I'm a consulting detective.
全世界独此一家，我发明的职业
Only one in the world. I invented the job.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是警察束手无策时 这是常有的
It means when the police are out of their depth, which is always,
他们就咨询我
they consult me.
警察不会咨询业余人员
The police don't consult amateurs.
我昨天第一次见到你时
When I met you for the first time yesterday,
我说是阿富汗还是伊拉克
I said Afghanistan or Iraq.
- 你看起来很惊讶  - 对，你怎么知道的
- You looked surprised. - Yes, how did you know?
我不知道，我看到
I didn't know, I saw.
你的发型，站立姿势说明是军人
Your haircut, the way you hold yourself says military.
- 但你说的话...  - 跟我那会儿有点不一样了
- But your conversation... - Bit different from my day.
说明在巴茨医院受训过  所以显然是军医
...said trained at Barts - so Army doctor, obvious.
你的脸晒黑了
Your face is tanned...
但手腕以上却没晒黑
but no tan above the wrists.
说明你从国外回来  但不是日光浴
You've been abroad, but not sunbathing.
你走路时跛得厉害
Your limp's really bad when you walk,
站立时却没要一把椅子，好像你忘了这事
but you don't ask for a chair when you stand, like you've forgotten about it,
所以多少有一部分是心理问题
so it's at least partly psychosomatic.
那说明受伤的原始环境是外伤
That says the original circumstances of the injury were traumatic.
是战斗负伤，战斗负伤
Wounded in action, then. Wounded in action,
晒黑  那就是阿富汗或伊拉克
suntan - Afghanistan or Iraq.
你说我在看心理咨询
You said I had a therapist.
你的跛脚是身心失调，当然要心理咨询
You've got a psychosomatic limp, of course you've got a therapist.
再说你的兄弟
Then there's your brother.
你的手机，很贵，能收发邮件，放MP3
Your phone. It's expensive, e-mail enabled, MP3 player.
你在找人合租，不会是自己买的，那么它是个礼物
You're looking for a flatshare. You wouldn't buy this - it's a gift then.
有刮痕  不止一两条  而是很多
Scratches. Not one, many over time -
肯定是跟钥匙硬币放在同一个口袋
it's been in the same pocket as keys and coins.
你不会这样对自己的奢侈品
You wouldn't treat your one luxury item like this,
所以它以前有个主人
so it's had a previous owner.
下一个就简单了  你已经知道了
Next bit's easy. You know it already.
刻的字吗
The engraving?
海瑞·华生，明显是一个家庭成员给了你他的旧手机
Harry Watson. Clearly a family member who's given you his old phone.
不是你父亲，这是年轻人款式
Not your father, this is a young man's gadget.
可能是表兄弟，但你是战斗英雄，找不到地方住
Could be a cousin, but you're a war hero who can't find a place to live.
不太可能你有个大家庭，当然不是你亲近的人
Unlikely you've got an extended family, certainly not one you're close to.
那就是你兄弟
So brother it is.
现在说克拉拉，谁是克拉拉？
Now, Clara, who's Clara?
“三个吻”说明两人是爱情关系
Three kisses says it's a romantic attachment.
手机昂贵，说明是妻子，不是女友
The expense of the phone says wife, not girlfriend.
肯定是最近才送的，这一款才发布六个月
Must have given it to him recently, the model's only six months old.
那就是婚姻出了问题  才用了六个月就送人
Marriage in trouble, then - six months on he's given it away.
如果是她离开他，他就会留着，人之常情，多愁善感
If she'd left him, he would have kept it. Peaple do, sentiment.
不，他想甩掉它，是他离开了她
No, he wanted rid of it. He left her.
他把手机给了你，那说明他想跟你保持联系
He gave the phone to you, so he wants you to stay in touch.
你在找便宜住处
You're looking for cheap accommodation,
却不去向自己兄弟求助
but not going to your brother for help.
这说明你跟他之间有问题
That says you've got problems with him.
也许是你喜欢他妻子，也许是你讨厌他喝酒
Maybe you liked his wife or maybe you don't like his drinking.
你怎么可能知道喝酒的事？
How can you possibly know about the drinking?
瞎猜的，不过猜得很好
Shot in the dark. Good one, though.
电源插口  周围有细小的磨损痕迹
Power connection - tiny little scuff marks round the edge.
每晚他插上充电  但手总是在抖
Every night he goes to plug it in to charge, but his hands are shaking.
你绝不会在清醒的人手机上看到这种痕迹
You never see those marks on a sober man's phone,
醉鬼的手机上则绝不会没有，所以，瞧，你说得对
never see a drunk's without them. There you go, you were right.
我说得对？我说对了什么？
I was right? Right about what?
警察不会请教业余人员
The police don't consult amateurs.
这真是…太了不起了
That...was amazing.
- 你这么觉得吗？  - 当然是了
- Do you think so? - Of course it was.
这是非凡的，非同凡响
It was extraordinary, quite extraordinary.
- 别人一般不这么说  - 别人一般说什么？
- That's not what people normally say. - What do people normally say?
滚开
Piss off!
我有没有弄错什么？
Did I get anything wrong?
海瑞和我相处不来，从没好过
Harry and me don't get on, never have.
克拉拉和海瑞分手了，三个月前
Clara and Harry split up three months ago
他们正在办离婚
and they're getting a divorce.
而且海瑞是个酒徒
And Harry is a drinker.
那就是全中，我倒没期望事事都对
Spot on, then. I didn't expect to be right about everything.
海瑞是海莉特的昵称
Harry's short for Harriet.
海瑞是你姐姐
Harry's your sister.
- 我来这到底该干嘛来着？  - 姐姐
- What exactly am I supposed to be doing here? - Sister!
- 不，说真的，我来干嘛？  - 总是有点错
- No, seriously, what am I doing here? - There's always something.
你好  怪胎
Hello, freak!
我来找雷斯垂德探长
I'm here to see Detective Inspector Lestrade.
为什么
Why?
我是受邀前来
I was invited.
- 为什么？  - 我想他要我来看看
- Why? - I think he wants me to take a look.
- 你知道我的想法，对吧  - 一向知道，萨莉
- You know what I think, don't you? - Always, Sally.
我甚至知道你昨晚没回家
I even know you didn't make it home last night.
- 我没…这位是谁？  - 我同事  华生医生
- Er...who's this? - Colleague of mine, Dr Watson.
华生医生  这位是萨莉·多诺万警佐
Dr Watson, Sergeant Sally Donovan.
老朋友
Old friend.
一个同事？你怎么会有同事？
A colleague? How do you get a colleague?
怎么？他跟踪你回家了？
What? Did he follow you home?
- 我在这里等着是不是更好  - 不
- Would it be better if I just waited...? - No.
怪胎来了 我带他进去
Freak's here. Bringing him in.
哦，安德森，又见面了
Ah, Anderson. Here we are again.
这是犯罪现场，我不想它被污染，说清楚了吗
It's a crime scene. I don't want it contaminated. Are we clear on that?
清楚得很
Quite clear.
你妻子很久不回家了吧？
And is your wife away for long?
别装得像你自己推理出来的，有人告诉你的吧
Oh, don't pretend you worked that out. Somebody told you that.
你的体香剂告诉我的
Your deodorant told me that.
- 我的体香剂？  - 是男用的
- My deodorant? - It's for men.
当然是男用的，就是我在用啊
Well, of course it's for men - I'm wearing it.
多诺万警佐也用了
So's Sergeant Donovan.
哦，它刚挥发掉了，我能进去了吗
Ooh...I think it just vaporised. May I go in?
- 听着，不管你在暗示什么  - 我什么都没暗示
- Now, look, whatever you're trying to imply... - I'm not implying anything.
我肯定萨莉只是顺道找你聊个小天
I'm sure Sally came round for a nice little chat
再碰巧过了个夜
and just happened to stay over.
我猜她还替你擦了地板，从她膝盖的状况来看
And I assume she scrubbed your floors, going by the state of her knees.
你得穿一件这衣服
You'll need to wear one of these.
这是哪位？
Who's this?
他跟我一起的
He's with me.
- 但他究竟是谁？  - 我说了跟我一起的
- But who is he? - I said he's with me.
你不穿一件吗？
Aren't you going to put one on?
- 我们去哪？  - 楼上
- So where are we? - Upstairs.
我可以给你两分钟
I can give you two minutes.
可能要更久
May need longer.
她名叫詹妮弗·威尔逊，根据她的信用卡
Her name's Jennifer Wilson, according to her credit cards.
我们正根据信用卡查她的联系方式
We're running them now for contact details.
时间还没过太久
Hasn't been here long.
几个孩子发现的
Some kids found her.
闭嘴
Shut up.
- 我什么也没说  - 你在思考，很吵
- I didn't say anything. - You were thinking. It's annoying.
有发现吗？
Got anything?
不太多
Not much.
她是德国人
She's German.
Rache 是德语的复仇  她可能想告诉我们...
Rache. It's German for revenge. She could be trying to tell us...
好了，感谢参与
Yes, thank you for your input.
- 她是德国人吗？  - 当然不是  不过倒是外地来的
- So she's German? - Of course she's not. She's from out of town, though.
打算在回加迪夫的家之前
Intended to stay in London for one night
在伦敦小住一夜，很明显
before returning home to Cardiff - so far, so obvious.
- 什么，很明显？  - 那这条信息呢？
- Sorry, obvious? - What about the message, though?
华生医生，你怎么看？
Dr Watson, what do you think?
- 那条信息吗？  - 尸体，你是医务人员
- Of the message? - Of the body. You're a medical man.
我们外面有一队人呢
We have a whole team outside.
他们不和我一起工作
They won't work with me.
我坏了所有规矩放你进来
I'm breaking every rule letting you in here...
是的，因为你需要我
Yes, because you need me.
是的，是这样
Yes, I do.
老天帮帮我
God help me.
华生医生
Dr Watson!
哦，按他说的做  请便
Oh, do as he says. Help yourself.
安德森，让大家在外面多等几分钟
Anderson, keep everyone out for a couple of minutes...
- 好吧  - 要我在这儿做什么
- Well? - What am I doing here?
帮我理清思路
Helping me make a point.
我本是帮你分担房租的
I'm supposed to help you pay the rent.
这更好玩
This is more fun.
好玩？一个女人横死在这里
Fun? There's a woman lying dead.
完美的分析  不过我希望你再深入些
Perfectly sound analysis, but I was hoping you'd go deeper.
对...窒息...可能
Yeah... Asphyxiation...probably.
昏倒，被她自己的呕吐物噎住
Passed out, choked on her own vomit.
她身上闻不出酒精
Can't smell any alcohol on her.
可以是癫痫发作  可能是药物
It could have been a seizure. Possibly drugs.
你知道那是什么  你读过报纸
You know what it was, you've read the papers.
对，她是自杀者之一，第四个...
Well, she's one of the suicides. The fourth...?
夏洛克  我说过你2分钟
Sherlock, two minutes, I said.
我需要你的发现
I need anything you've got.
死者年龄三十大几
Victim is in her late 30s.
职业女性  从她的衣着来看
Professional person, going by her clothes.
我猜是媒体业，根据那触目惊心的粉红色
I'm guessing something in the media, going by the frankly alarming shade of pink.
今天刚从加迪夫过来
Travelled from Cardiff today
打算在伦敦住一晚，看她手提箱的大小就知道了
intending to stay in London for one night from the size of her suitcase.
- 手提箱？  - 对  手提箱
- Suitcase? - Suitcase, yes.
她结婚起码10年  但不幸福
She's been married at least ten years, but not happily.
她有一串情人  但没一个知道她结婚了
She's had a string of lovers, but none of them knew she was married.
老天啊  这要都是你编出来...
Oh, for God's sake, if you're just making this up...
她的婚戒  起码已经有10年了
Her wedding ring. Ten years old at least.
她别的首饰都做过定期保养
The rest of herjewellery has been regularly cleaned,
而婚戒却没有  她的婚姻状况就是如此
but not her wedding ring. State of her marriage right there.
戒指的里圈要比外圈光亮许多
The inside is shinier than the outside,
说明经常拿下来
that means it's regularly removed.
戒指只有在她取下来时才会被磨亮
The only polishing it gets is when she works it off her finger.
不是为了工作，看看她的指甲
It's not for work, look at her nails.
她不是做手工活的
She doesn't work with her hands,
那她是为了什么或是谁取下戒指呢
so what or who does she remove her rings for?
显然不是一个情人
Clearly not one lover
她绝不能这么长时间编造单身身份
she'd never sustain the fiction of being single for that long,
- 因此肯定不止一个  简单  - 厉害
- so more likely a string of them. Simple. - That's brilliant.
- 抱歉  - 加迪夫呢？
- Sorry. - Cardiff?
很明显，不是吗
It's obvious, isn't it?
对我不明显
It's not obvious to me.
神啊，你那可笑的小脑袋是啥样？一定蛮无聊的
Dear God, what is it like in your funny little brains? It must be so boring.
她的外套
Her coat
有点潮湿  几小时前她一定淋了场大雨
it's slightly damp, she's been in heavy rain in the last few hours -
当时伦敦任何地方都没下雨
no rain anywhere in London in that time.
外套领子下面也是湿的
Under her coat collar is damp too.
她曾把领子立起来挡风
She's turned it up against the wind.
她左边口袋里有把伞  但是干的  没用过
She's got an umbrella in her left pocket, but it's dry and unused.
不单有风 是大风  大到无法撑伞
Not just wind, strong wind - too strong to use her umbrella.
我们从她的手提箱可知，她准备过夜
We know from her suitcase that she was intending to stay overnight
所以她一定来自远方
so she must come distance
但她不可能已外出超过两三个小时
but she can't have travelled more than two or three hours,
因为她的外套还没干
because her coat still hasn't dried.
所以 在其旅行时间半径内 什么地方曾有过大风大雨？
So, where has there been heavy rain and strong wind within the radius of that travel time?
加迪夫
Cardiff.
- 太神奇了  - 你知道自己说出声来了吗
- That's fantastic. - Do you know you do that out loud?
- 抱歉 我会闭嘴的  - 不  没关系
- Sorry, I'll shut up. - No, it's...fine.
你为什么总提到手提箱？
Why do you keep saying suitcase?
对，它在哪里？
Yes, where is it?
她肯定带了手机或是电子本
She must have had a phone or an organiser.
查出瑞琪儿是何人
Find out who Rachel is.
她写的是瑞琪儿？
She was writing Rachel?
不，她写的是复仇的德语
No, she was leaving an angry note in German!
当然写的是瑞琪儿 不可能是别的字
Of course she was writing Rachel, no other word it can be.
问题是她为何要等到临死前才写这个
But the question is why did she wait until she was dying to write it?
你怎么知道她有个手提箱？
How do you know she had a suitcase?
看看右腿
Look at the right leg.
右脚踝和小腿上有小泥点，而左腿上没有
Tiny splash marks on her right heel and calf not present on the left.
她用右手拖着个轮式手提箱在后面
She was dragging a wheeled suitcase behind her with her right hand.
那些泥点没有飞到别处
Don't get that splash pattern any other way.
是短小的箱子，根据泥点分布
Smallish case, going by the spread.
那种尺寸的箱子，这样穿着的女人
Case that size, woman this clothes-conscious -
只可能是一只过夜旅行箱
could only be an overnight bag
所以我们知道她打算过一夜
so we know she was staying one night.
它在哪里？你们检查过了吗
Where is it? What have you done with it?
没有箱子
There wasn't a case.
再说一次
Say that again.
没有箱子，这里根本就没有什么手提箱
There wasn't a case. There was never any suitcase.
手提箱，有谁见过一个手提箱？
Suitcase! Did anyone find a suitcase?
这房子里有手提箱吗
Was there a suitcase in this house?
夏洛克，这里没有箱子
Sherlock, there was no case!
但他们自己服毒
But they take the poison themselves,
他们自己选择吞下药丸
they choose swallow the pills themselves.
迹象明显，就算是你的手下也不可能错过
There are clear signs, even you lot couldn't miss them.
好吧  谢谢  还有呢
Right, thanks. And...?
是谋杀，全都是，我还没搞清
It's murder, all of them. I don't know how.
但绝不是自杀，是他杀，连环杀人案
But they're not suicides, they're killings, they're serial killings.
一个连环杀人犯，我爱死了
We've got a serial killer. Love those.
总能让人有各种期待
There's always something to look forward to.
你为什么这么说？
Why are you saying that?
她的箱子，拜托，她的箱子在哪里？
Her case! Come on, where is her case?
是她吃了吗？
Did she eat it?
另有别人来过这里，并拿走了她的箱子
Someone else was here and they took her case.
所以凶手必是驱车至此
So the killer must have driven here.
忘了箱子在车上
Forgot the case was in the car.
她也可能先入住酒店，把箱子留在那里
She could have checked into a hotel, left it there.
不，她从没到过酒店，看看她的头发
No, she never got to the hotel. Look at her hair.
她的颜色搭配，唇彩和鞋子
She colour-coordinates her lipstick and shoes.
她绝不会那样离开酒店，她的头发还…
She'd never have left any hotel with her hair still looking...
夏洛克，是什么，是什么？
Sherlock? What is it, what?
连环杀人犯总是很难搞
Serial killers, always hard.
你得等他们犯一个错误
You have to wait for them to make a mistake.
我们不能光等着
We can't just wait!
等待已经结束了，看看她，仔细看
Oh, we're done waiting. Look at her, really look!
休斯顿，我们有错误了  快去加迪夫
Houston, we have a mistake. Get on to Cardiff.
找到詹妮弗·威尔逊的家人和朋友在哪
Find out who Jennifer Wilson's family and friends were.
找到瑞琪儿
Find Rachel!
当然，好  但是什么错误？
Of course, yeah - but what mistake?!
粉色
Pink!
我们开工
Let's get on with it...
- 他走了  - 夏洛克·福尔摩斯吗？
- He's gone. - Who, Sherlock Holmes?
对，他刚走，他总这样
Yeah, he just took off. He does that.
- 他还会回来吗？  - 看来不会
- Is he coming back? - Didn't look like it.
好吧
Right.
Right...
好，打扰了，我在哪里？
Yes. Sorry, where am I?
布里克斯顿
Brixton.
我…你知道我能在哪儿打到车吗
I...Do you know where I could get a cab?
只是…
It's just, er...
那个…我的腿
well... my leg.
试试主路上
try the main road.
谢谢
Thanks.
可你不是他的朋友
But you're not his friend.
他没有朋友
He doesn't have friends.
所以你是谁呢？
So who are you?
我…我谁也不是，我刚认识他
I'm...I'm nobody. I just met him.
好吧，一点忠告，离那人远点
OK, bit of advice, then. Stay away from that guy.
为什么？
Why?
你知道他为什么来这里吗？
You know why he's here?
他没有报酬什么的
He's not paid or anything.
他喜欢这个，他乐在其中
He likes it. He gets off on it.
犯罪越古怪，他越享受，而且知道吗？
The weirder the crime, the more he gets off. And you know what...?
总有一天，揭露犯罪不再能满足他
One day just showing up won't be enough.
总有一天，我们会站在一具尸体边
One day we'll be standing round a body,
而夏洛克·福尔摩斯便是抛尸之人
and Sherlock Holmes'll be the one that put it there.
- 他为什么会这么做？  - 因为他就是个疯子
- Why would he do that? - Because he's a psychopath.
疯子容易无聊
Psychopaths get bored.
- 多诺万  - 来了
- Donovan! - Coming.
离夏洛克·福尔摩斯远点
Stay away from Sherlock Holmes.
出租车 出租车
Taxi! Taxi...
喂
Hello?
有个监控摄像头在你左边大楼上
There is a security camera on the building to your left.
你看到了吗
Do you see it?
你是谁？
Who's this?
谁在说话？
Who's speaking?
你看到那个摄像头了吗，华生医生？
Do you see the camera, Dr Watson?
- 对，我看到了  - 看好
- Yeah, I see it. - Watch...
还有一个摄像头在你对面的房子上
There is another camera on the building opposite you.
看到了吗
Do you see it?
最后，在你右边的楼顶上
And finally, at the top of the building on your right.
你怎么做到的？
How are you doing this?
上车，华生医生
Get into the car, Dr Watson.
我不想发什么威胁
I would make some sort of threat,
但我肯定你相当清楚自己的处境
but I'm sure your situation is quite clear to you.
- 你好  - 嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name, then?
哦…安茜娅
Er...Anthea.
这是你的真名吗？
Is that your real name?
不是
No.
我叫约翰
I'm John.
对，我知道
Yes. I know.
问这个有意义吗…我要去哪里？
Any point in asking...where I'm going?
完全没有
None at all...
约翰
John.
好吧
Ok.
请坐，约翰
Have a seat, John.
你知道，我有手机
You know, I've got a phone.
我是说，你那些搞得很聪明
I mean, very clever and all that,
但是
but, er...
你可以直接打给我
you could just phone me.
打我手机
On my phone.
人要避开夏洛克·福尔摩斯的注意
When one is avoiding the attention of Sherlock Holmes,
就得谨慎些，所以挑了这地方
one learns to be discreet, hence this place.
你的腿一定很疼，坐吧
Your leg must be hurting you. Sit down.
我不想坐下
I don't want to sit down.
你看起来不太害怕
You don't seem very afraid.
你看起来不太吓人
You don't seem very frightening.
是啊
Yes...
军人的勇敢
The bravery of the soldier.
“勇敢”其实是“愚蠢”一词的仁慈说法，你不觉得吗
Bravery is by far the kindest word for stupidity, don't you think?
你跟夏洛克·福尔摩斯是何关系？
What is your connection to Sherlock Holmes?
没有，我几乎不认识他，我跟他结识是在…
I don't have one. I barely know him. I met him...
昨天
yesterday.
呣，既然你昨天搬进他那里
Mmm, and since yesterday, you've moved in with him
现在你俩就一起查案
and now you're solving crimes together.
也许我们可以期待到周末有个订婚喜讯？
Might we expect a happy announcement by the end of the week?
- 你是谁？  - 利害相关方罢了
- Who are you? - An interested party.
与夏洛克相关？为何？
Interested in Sherlock? Why?
我猜你们不是朋友
I'm guessing you're not friends.
你见过他了，你能想象他有几个朋友？
You've met him. How many friends do you imagine he has?
我是夏洛克·福尔摩斯所能拥有的，最接近于“朋友”的东西
I am the closest thing to a friend that Sherlock Holmes is capable of having.
那是啥？
And what's that?
- 一个敌人  - 一个敌人？
- An enemy. - An enemy?
当然，是他心目中的
In his mind, certainly.
如果你去问他，他可能会说是他的死敌
If you were to ask him, he'd probably say his arch-enemy.
他确实爱搞戏剧化
He does love to be dramatic.
谢谢老天，你倒不戏剧化
Well, thank God you're above all that
希望我没有让你分心
I hope I'm not distracting you.
完全没有让我分心
Not distracting me at all.
你计划继续与夏洛克·福尔摩斯交往吗？
Do you plan to continue your association with Sherlock Holmes?
我可能说错了
I could be wrong...
但是…我认为这不是你操心的事
but I think that's none of your business.
- 可能是  - 真的不可能
- It could be. - It really couldn't.
如果你真的搬入…
If you do move into, um...
贝克街221B
...22 1 B Baker Street,
我将乐意定期给你提供一笔可观的费用，用以…
I'd be happy to pay you a meaningful sum of money on a regular basis
替你分忧
to ease your way.
为何？
Why?
因为你不是有钱人
Because you're not a wealthy man.
以此交换什么？
In exchange for what?
情报
Information.
无非分请求  不会让你感到…为难
Nothing indiscreet. Nothing you'd feel...uncomfortable with.
只需告诉我他在干什么
Just tell me what he's up to.
为什么
Why?
我担心他，时不时地
I worry about him. Constantly.
你真好
That's nice of you.
不过出于各种理由，我宁愿我的关心不被提起
But I would prefer for various reasons that my concern go unmentioned.
我们的关系你也许可以称之为…艰难
We have what you might call a... difficult relationship.
- 不  - 可我还没提具体数字呢
- No. - But I haven't mentioned a figure.
不必费心了
Don't bother.
你非常忠诚，非常果断
You're very loyal very quickly.
不，我不是，我只是没兴趣
No, I'm not, I'm just not interested.
“信任危机” ，这里写着
"Trust issues", it says here.
那是什么？
What's that?
可不可以说 你已决定在所有人中信任夏洛克·福尔摩斯了？
Could it be that you've decided to trust Sherlock Holmes of all people?
谁说我信任他了？
Who says I trust him?
你不像善交朋友的人
You don't seem the kind to make friends easily.
咱们说完了吗
Are we done?
你说呢
You tell me.
我想有人已警告过你远离他
I imagine people have already warned you to stay away from him,
不过我能从你的左手看出 你不会那么做
but I can see from your left hand that's not going to happen.
- 我的什么？  - 给我看看
- My what? - Show me.
不要…
Don't...
- 不一般  - 什么东西？
- Remarkable. - What is?
多数人在这城里东奔西撞
Most people blunder round this city
他们所见只有街道、商铺和汽车
and all they see are streets and shops and cars.
你和夏洛克·福尔摩斯一起行走时，你看到了战场
When you walk with Sherlock Holmes, you see the battlefield.
你已经看到了，对吗？
You've seen it already, haven't you?
我的手怎么了？
What's wrong with my hand?
你的左手有间歇性颤抖
You have an intermittent tremor in your left hand.
你的理疗师认为那是创后应激障碍
Your therapist thinks it's post-traumatic stress disorder.
她认为你被军役生涯的记忆所纠缠
She thinks you're haunted by memories of your military service.
你到底是谁？
Who the hell are you?
这你怎么能知道？
How do you know that?
辞了她，她完全搞错了
Fire her. She's got it the wrong way round.
你现在就处于压力下，而你的手完全稳定
You're under stress right now, and your hand is perfectly steady.
你不是受战争困扰，华生医生
You're not haunted by the war, Dr Watson...
你想念它
You miss it.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
是时候选一边了，华生医生
Time to choose a side, Dr Watson.
我来送你回家
I'm to take you home.
地址？
Address?
贝克街
Er, Baker Street.
贝克街221B
22 1 B Baker Street.
不过我得先去个地方
But I need to stop off somewhere first.
听着，你的老板
Listen, your boss.
有没有可能你不告诉他这是我来的地方？
Any chance you could not tell him this is where I went?
- 可以  - 你已经告诉他了，对吧
- Sure. - You've told him already, haven't you?
对
Yeah.
你有没有什么空闲时间？
do you ever get any free time?
有，很多
Oh, yeah. Lots.
- 拜  - 好
- Bye. - OK.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
尼古丁贴片
Nicotine patch.
帮助我思考
Helps me think.
这年头在伦敦 不可能维持吸烟的习惯
Impossible to sustain a smoking habit in London these days.
对脑力劳动是坏消息
Bad news for brain work.
对呼吸是好消息
It's good news for breathing.
呼吸，呼吸太无聊
Oh, breathing! Breathing's boring.
那是…三片吗？
Is that...three patches?
这是三片难度的问题
It's a three-patch problem.
嗯
Well...?
你要我回来  我想是要紧事
You asked me to come, I'm assuming it's important.
对  当然  我能借用你的手机吗？
Oh, yeah, of course. Can I borrow your phone?
我的手机？
My phone?
我的号码有可能被认出来
There's always a chance that my number will be recognised.
网站上有
It's on the website.
哈德森太太有手机
Mrs Hudson's got a phone.
对，她在楼下
Yeah, she's downstairs.
我试过喊了，但她没听见
I tried shouting, but she didn't hear.
我当时在伦敦另一头
I was the other side of London...
这不急
There was no hurry.
给...
Here...
那么，那个箱子怎么了
So what's this about the case?
- 她的箱子  - 她的箱子？
- Her case... - Her case?
她的手提箱，对，很明显
Her suitcase, yes, obviously.
凶手拿走她的手提箱  第一个大错
The murderer took her suitcase, first big mistake.
好吧，他拿了她的箱子，所以？
OK, he took her case. So?
这没用，没别的办法了，我们得冒个险
It's no use, there's no other way. We'll have to risk it.
我书桌上有个手机号  我要你发个短信
On my desk there's a number. I want you to send a text.
你叫我回来…就发个短信？
You've brought me here... to send a text.
短信，对，号码在我桌上
Text, yes. The number on my desk.
- 怎么了？  - 刚才见了你一位朋友
- What's wrong? - Just met a friend of yours.
- 一个朋友？  - 一个敌人
- A friend? - An enemy.
哦，哪个？
Oh. Which one?
你的死敌，他说的
Well, your arch-enemy, according to him.
人会有死敌吗？
Do people have arch-enemies?
他是不是给你钱来监视我？
Did he offer you money to spy on me?
- 是的  - 你收了吗？
- Yes. - Did you take it?
没
No.
可惜，我们可以把钱分了，下次要三思
Pity, we could have split the fee. Think it through next time.
他是谁？
Who is he?
你见过的最危险人物 但不是我现在的问题
The most dangerous man you've ever met and not my problem right now.
我桌上 手机号
On my desk, the number!
詹妮弗·威尔逊，这是...
Jennifer Wilson. That was...
等等，这不是那个女死者吗
Hang on. Wasn't that the dead woman?
是的，这不重要，输这个号码就好
Yes. That's not important. Just enter the number.
- 你在输吗  - 对
- Are you doing it? - Yes.
- 输完了吗  - 是的，等等
- Have you done it? - Yeah, hang on!
一字不差输这些
These words exactly.
“劳瑞斯顿花园发生了什么事
"What happened at Lauriston Gardens?
我一定是昏过去了
"I must have blacked out.
诺森伯兰大街22号  请快过来”
"22 Northumberland Street, please come."
- 你昏过去了吗  - 什么？没有...没有
- You blacked out? - What? No... No!
输入然后发送 快
Type and send it. Quickly.
- 发送了吗  - 地址是？
- Have you sent it? - What's the address?
诺森伯兰大街22号  赶紧的
22 Northumberland Street. Hurry up!
这是...
That's...
这是粉衣女士的箱子，詹妮弗·威尔逊的箱子
That's the pink lady's case, that's Jennifer Wilson's case.
是的，显然
Yes, obviously.
也许我该提一下  我没杀她
Oh, perhaps I should mention - I didn't kill her.
- 我从没说是你  - 为什么不是
- I never said you did. - Why not?
鉴于我刚让你发的那短信，而我事实上又有她的箱子
Given that text I just had you send and the fact I have her case,
这是完全合乎逻辑的假设
it's a perfectly logical assumption.
人们通常把你看成凶手吗
Do people usually assume you're the murderer?
时不时会
Now and then, yes.
好吧
Ok...
- 你从哪弄来的？  - 找到的
- How did you get this? - By looking.
哪里
Where?
凶手一定是开车带她到劳瑞斯顿花园
The killer must have driven her to Lauriston Gardens.
他碰巧留下箱子只可能是因为它在车里
He could only keep her case by accident if it was in a car.
没人能带着这箱子而不引人注目
Nobody could be seen with this case without drawing attention to himself
尤其是男人 这在统计学上更可能
particularly a man, which is statistically more likely.
所以显然 当他发现箱子还在 就急着处理掉它
So obviously he'd feel compelled to get rid of it with he noticed that he still had it
用不了五分钟 他就意识到自己的错误
Wouldn't have taken him more than five minutes to realise his mistake
我检查了劳瑞斯顿花园五分钟车程内每一条后巷
I checked every backstreet wide enough for a car five minutes from Lauriston Gardens
以及任何能不引起注意处理掉大件物品的地方
and anywhere you could dispose of a bulky object without being observed.
花了不到一小时就找到了
Took me less than an hour to find the right skip.
粉色，你推论出一切，就因为你认识到箱子会是粉色的吗
Pink. You got all that because you realised the case would be pink?
- 必须是粉色，显然  - 我怎么没想到
- It had to be pink, obviously. - Why didn't I think of that
因为你是傻瓜
Because you're an idiot.
不不，别这副表情，实际上人人都是
No, no, don't look like that. Practically everyone is.
现在看看  你发现少了什么吗
Now, look. Do you see what's missing?
箱子里吗？我怎么知道？
From the case? How could I?
她的电话  她的手机在哪里？
Her phone. Where's her mobile phone?
死者身上没手机  箱子里没有手机
There was no phone on the body, there's no phone in the case.
我们知道她有，就是你刚发短信的那个
We know she had one. That's the one there you just texted it.
也许她落在家里了
Maybe she left it at home.
她有一串情人  她对此很小心
She has a string of lovers and she's careful about it.
绝不会把手机落在家里
She never leaves her phone at home.
那我刚才发短信干嘛？
Er... Why did I just send that text?
问题是，她的手机现在哪里？
Well, the question is where is her phone now?
- 她可能弄丢了  - 对，或者？
- She could have lost it. - Yes, or?
那个凶手，你认为凶手拿着手机？
The murderer... You think the murderer has the phone?
也许她…把手机连同箱子落在车里
Maybe she...left it when she left her case.
也许他出于某种原因拿走了
Maybe he took it from her for some reason.
不管哪种，机率上倾向于凶手拿着她的手机
Either way, the balance of probability is the murderer has her phone.
抱歉…我们在做什么？
Sorry...what are we doing?
我刚才是不是给凶手发短信了？这么做有何好处？
Did I just text a murderer? What good will that do?
距离上一个受害者才几小时
A few hours after his last victim,
而现在他收到只可能来自她的短信
and now he receives a text that can only be from her.
如果只是某人捡到那手机，会忽略那样一条短信
If somebody had just found that phone, they'd ignore a text like that,
但那个凶手…
but the murderer...
会惊慌
would panic.
你告诉警方了吗？
Have you talked to the police?
已有四人遇害  没时间告诉警方
Four people are dead, there isn't time to talk to the police
那你为何告诉我？
So why are you talking to me?
哈德森太太拿走了我的骷髅
Mrs Hudson took my skull.
所以我主要是填补你的骷髅空虚？
So I'm basically filling in for your skull?
放心，你做得不错
Relax, you're doing fine.
- 那么…  - 那么什么？
- Well? - Well, what?
那么，你可以坐在那儿，看电视
Well...you could just sit there and...watch telly.
你要我跟你去吗？
You want me to come with you?
我出门喜欢有个伴，而且我大声说话时思考更佳
I like company when I go out and I think better when I talk aloud.
骷髅只会引人注目，所以…
The skull just attracts attention, so...
有问题？
Problem?
对，多诺万警佐
Yeah, Sergeant Donovan.
她怎么了
What about her?
她说，你沉迷于此，你享受其中
She said you get off on this, you enjoy it.
我也说过“有危险”  你也来了
And I said "Dangerous", and here you are.
该死
Damn it!
我们现在去哪里？
Where are we going?
诺森伯兰街，从这走路五分钟
Northumberland Street's a five-minute walk from here.
你真认为他会蠢到去那里吗？
You think he's stupid enough to go there?
不，我认为他够聪明
No, I think he's brilliant enough.
我爱那些聪明的
I love the brilliant ones.
他们都极其渴望被抓
They're all so desperate to get caught.
- 为什么？  - 赞赏
- Why? - Appreciation!
喝彩！ 最终成为焦点人物
Applause! At long last the spotlight.
那是天才们的弱点，约翰，需要一个观众
That's the frailty of genius, John, it needs an audience.
是啊
Yeah.
这就是他的猎场
This is his hunting ground.
就在这里，在城市的心脏
Right here in the heart of the city.
既然我们知道他的受害者是被劫持的
Now that we know his victims were abducted,
这改变了一切
that changes everything.
因为他所有的受害者都消失在闹市街头
Because all of his victims disappeared from busy streets, crowded places,
可没人看见他们消失
but nobody saw them go.
想想，谁是我们即便不认识也信任的人
Think! Who do we trust, even though we don't know them?
谁去哪里都不引人注意？
Who passes unnoticed wherever they go?
谁在人群当中狩猎？
Who hunts in the middle of a crowd?
不知道  谁？
Don't know. Who?
茫无头绪，饿吗？
Haven't the faintest. Hungry?
谢谢，比利
Thank you, Billy.
诺森伯兰街22号
22 Northumberland Street.
留心盯着
Keep your eyes on it.
他不会直接去按门铃，那得疯了才会
He's not just going to ring the doorbell. He'd need to be mad.
他已杀了四个人
He has killed four people.
好吧
Ok.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
菜单上有的，不管你想吃什么，免费
Anything on the menu, whatever you want, free.
店里买单，给你和你的约会对象
On the house, for you and for your date.
- 你想吃东西吗  - 我不是他的对象
- Do you want to eat? - I'm not his date.
这人帮我洗脱了谋杀嫌疑
This man got me off a murder charge.
这位是安杰洛
This is Angelo.
三年前我向雷斯垂德成功证实…
Three years ago, I successful proved to Lestrade,
一起恶性三重谋杀案发生时
at the time of a particularly vicious triple murder,
安杰洛正在城里别的地方，入室行劫
that Angelo was in a different part of town, house-breaking.
- 他清洗了我的名誉  - 我洗刷了一点
- He cleared my name. - I cleared it a bit.
对街有情况吗
Anything happening opposite?
没有
Nothing.
要不是这个人，我就得进监狱了
But for this man, I'd have gone to prison.
你是进了监狱
You did go to prison.
我拿支蜡烛放桌上，更浪漫点
I'll get a candle for the table. It's more romantic.
我不是他对象
I'm not his date!
你最好吃点  我们可能得等很久
You may as well eat. We might have a long wait.
谢谢
Thanks.
一般人没有死敌
People don't have arch-enemies.
- 说啥？  - 在现实生活中
- I'm sorry? - In real life.
现实中不存在死敌  没这种事
There are no arch-enemies in real life. Doesn't happen.
没有吗？ 听起来有点闷
Doesn't it? Sounds a bit dull.
所以我遇见了谁？
So who did I meet?
那么常人有什么，在“真实生活”中
What do real people have, then, in their..."real lives"?
朋友？
Friends?
认识的人  喜欢的人  不喜欢的人
People they know, people they like, people they don't like...
- 女朋友或男朋友  - 对，正如我所说 闷
- Girlfriends, boyfriends. - Yes, well, as I was saying, dull.
这么说你没有女朋友？
You don't have a girlfriend, then?
女朋友？没有，算不上是我的范畴
Girlfriend? No, not really my area.
哦，好吧
Mm. Oh, right.
那你有男朋友吗？这其实也没关系
Do you have a boyfriend? Which is fine, by the way.
我知道没关系
I know it's fine.
- 那你有男朋友？  - 没有
- So you've got a boyfriend, then. - No.
好的  懂了
Right. OK.
你是独一个 跟我一样
You're unattached. Like me.
好  不错
Fine. Good.
约翰…我想你应该了解
John, um...I think you should know
我当自己与工作结婚了  虽然我受宠若惊
I consider myself married to my work and while I'm flattered,
- 但是我真的不是要找...  - 不  我不是在问  不
- I'm really not looking for any... - No, I'm...not asking. No.
我只是在说  全都没关系
I'm just saying, it's all fine.
很好
Good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
看对街 出租车 停下了
Look across the street. Taxi. It's stopped.
没人上车  也没人下车
Nobody getting in and nobody getting out.
为什么是出租车？
Why a taxi?
哦，聪明啊
Oh, that's clever.
- 这样聪明吗？这样为什么聪明？  - 那是他？
- Is it clever? Why is it clever? - That's him.
- 别盯着看  - 你也在盯着
- Don't stare. - You're staring.
咱俩不能都盯着
We can't both stare.
抱歉
Sorry...
- 我记下车牌号码了  - 做得好
- I've got the cab number. - Good for you.
右转  单行道  道路施工 交通灯  公交车道
Right turn, one way, roadworks, traffic lights, bus lane,
人行横道  只准左转  交通灯
pedestrian crossing, left turn only, traffic lights.
替代路线
抱歉
Sorry.
道路关闭
跟上 约翰
Come on, John...
停
来啊 约翰 我们要跟丢了
Come on, John. We're losing him!
威斯敏斯特区
莱克星敦大街  西1
道路关闭
这边
This way.
不，这边
No, this way!
抱歉
Sorry...
步行区截止
禁止进入
威斯敏斯特区 莱克星敦大街 西1
路面塌陷  请绕行
警察  开门
Police! Open her up.
终点
不
No...
牙齿，晒黑，怎么，加州人吗
Teeth, tan. What, Californian?
洛杉矶圣莫尼卡  刚到
LA, Santa Monica. Just arrived.
- 你怎么可能知道？  - 行李牌
- How could you possibly know that? - The luggage.
你是第一次来伦敦，对吧
First trip to London, right?
让的哥载着你四处找目的地吧
Going by your final destination and the cabbie's taking you?
抱歉，你们是警察吗？
Sorry, are you guys the police?
对，一切还好吧？
Yeah. Everything all right?
好
Yeah.
欢迎来到伦敦
Welcome to London.
有任何问题，就知会我们
Er, any problems, just let us know.
基本上只是一辆碰巧慢下来的出租车
Basically just a cab that happened to slow down.
- 基本上  - 不是那凶手
- Basically. - Not the murderer.
- 不是那凶手，不是  - 国家不对 很好的不在现场证明
- Not the murderer, no. - Wrong country, good alibi.
- 他们走了  - 你从哪弄来的这个
- As they go. - Hey, where did you get this?
- 雷斯垂德探长？  - 对
- Detective Inspector Lestrade? - Yeah.
他一烦人我就掏他口袋
I pickpocket him when he's annoying.
你留着那个，我还有很多在公寓里
You can keep that one, I've got plenty at the flat.
什么？
What?
没什么，只是…“欢迎来到伦敦”
Nothing, just..."Welcome to London."
- 气喘上来了吗？  - 随时都可以
- Got your breath back? - Ready when you are.
这真荒唐
That was ridiculous.
这是我干过最荒唐的事，有生以来
That was the most ridiculous thing... I've ever done.
你可是入侵过阿富汗的
And you invaded Afghanistan.
那可不止我一个
That wasn't just me.
我们为何不回餐厅？
Why aren't we back at the restaurant?
他们会盯着的
They can keep an eye out.
反正机会不大
It was a long shot anyway.
那我们刚才去那里干嘛？
So what were we doing there?
只是打发时间
Oh, just passing the time.
还证明一个观点
And proving a point.
- 什么观点？  - 你
- What point? - You.
哈德森太太，华生医生要楼上的房间
Mrs Hudson! Dr Watson willtake the room upstairs.
谁说的？
Says who?
门外的人说的
Says the man at the door.
夏洛克发短信给我
Sherlock texted me.
他说你忘了这个
He said you forgot this.
谢谢你
Er, thank you.
Thank you.
夏洛克，你干了什么？
Sherlock, what have you done?
- 哈德森太太？  - 楼上
- Mrs Hudson? - Upstairs.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我就知道你找到了箱子，我不笨
I knew you'd find the case, I'm not stupid.
你不能闯进我的公寓
You can't just break into my flat.
你不能擅留证据，况且我没闯进你的公寓
You can't withhold evidence - and I didn't break into your flat.
那你把这叫做什么？
What do you call this, then?
这是一次缉毒行动
It's a drugs bust.
你认真的？这个人 瘾君子？
Seriously? This guy - a junkie?
- 你还不了解他吗？  - 约翰
- Have you met him? - John...
我敢肯定你可以在这公寓搜查一天
I'm pretty sure you could search this flat all day,
也绝不会找到任何称得上娱乐消遣的东西
you wouldn't find anything you could call recreational.
- 约翰，你也许该闭嘴了  - 但是这…
- John, you probably want to shut up now. - But come on...
- 不…  - 什么？
- No... - What?
- 你？  - 闭嘴
- You? - Shut up!
- 我不是你的缉毒犬  - 不  安德森是我的缉毒犬
- I'm not your sniffer dog. - No, Anderson's my sniffer dog.
安德森，缉毒行动与你何干？
Anderson, what are you doing here on a drugs bust?
我自愿来的
Oh, I volunteered.
他们都是自愿的，他们严格来说不是缉毒组的
They all did. They're not strictly speaking on the drug squad,
但他们很敏锐
but they're very keen.
- 这些是人眼睛吗？  - 放回去
- Are these human eyes? - Put those back!
- 它们在微波炉里  - 是个实验
- They were in the microwave. - It's an experiment.
继续搜，伙计们
Keep looking, guys.
或者你可以用适当的方式帮我们，我就让他们停下
Or you could help us properly, and I'll stand them down.
- 这真幼稚  - 对，我在跟个孩子打交道
- This is childish. - Well, I'm dealing with a child.
夏洛克，这是我们的案件
Sherlock, this is ourcase.
我让你参与，但你不能走开自己干
I'm letting you in, but you do not go off on your own.
清楚了吗
Clear?
否则怎样？所以你就设个假缉毒行动来欺压我？
Or what? So you set up a pretend drugs bust to bully me?
要是找到什么，就不是假的了
It stops being pretend if we find anything.
我是清白的
I am clean!
- 你的公寓呢？整个公寓？  - 我连烟都不抽
- Is your flat? All of it? - I don't even smoke.
我也不抽
Neither do I.
我们合作吧
So let's work together.
- 我们找到了瑞琪儿  - 她是谁？
- We've found Rachel. - Who is she?
詹妮弗·威尔逊的独女
Jennifer Wilson's only daughter.
她女儿？
Her daughter?
她为何写下女儿的名字？为什么？
Why would she write her daughter's name? Why?
管她呢  我们找到了箱子
Never mind that, we found the case.
据某人说，凶手拿着箱子
According to someone, the murderer has the case,
而我们发现它在我们最喜欢的精神病人手里
and we found it in the hands of our favourite psychopath.
不是精神病人，安德森
Not a psychopath, Andersen.
我是高智商反社会人格，做好调查
I'm a high-functioning sociopath. Do your research.
你需要带瑞琪儿来问询，我要问她
You need to bring Rachel in to question her. I need to question her.
- 她死了   - 好极了，如何，何时以及为何？
- She's dead. - Excellent. How, when and why?
是否有联系？一定有
Is there a connection? There has to be.
哦，我很怀疑，因为她已死了14年
Well, I doubt it, since she's been dead for 14 years.
严格来说 她从未活过
Technically, she was never alive.
瑞琪儿是詹妮弗·威尔逊的死胎女儿，14年前
Rachel was Jennifer Wilson's stillborn daughter, 14 years ago.
哦  那
Oh, that's...
那不对，怎么…
...that's not right. How...
她为何那么做？为什么？
Why would she do that? Why?
她为什么临死一刻想到女儿？
Why would she think of her daughter in her last moments?
是啊，反社会，这下我看到了
Yep - sociopath, I'm seeing it now.
她不是在想自己的女儿
She didn't think about her daughter.
她刻出这个名字，在地板上，用指甲
She scratched her name on the floor with her fingernails.
她快死了，这很费劲，会很痛苦
She was dying. It took effort, it would have hurt.
你说过受害人都是自行服毒
You said that the victims all took the poison themselves,
他让他们服毒的
that he makes them take it.
也许他...我不知道...跟他们说了什么
Well, maybe he...I don't know, talks to them.
也许他以某种方式利用了她女儿的死
Maybe he used the death of her daughter somehow.
可那是陈年旧事了，她为何还会心烦？
But that was ages ago. Why would she still be upset?
不好吗？
Not good?
有点不好，对
Bit not good, yeah.
如果你快死了  如果你被人谋杀
If you were dying, if you'd been murdered,
在你最后那几分钟里 你会说什么？
in your very last few seconds, what would you say?
- “求你，主啊，让我活着”  - 运用你的想象力
- "Please, God, let me live." - Use your imagination!
我没必要
I don't have to.
对，但如果你很聪明呢，真的很聪明
Yeah, but if you were clever, really clever.
詹妮弗·威尔逊操纵那么多情人，她很聪明
Jennifer Wilson running all those lovers - she was clever.
她是想告诉我们什么
She's trying to tell us something.
不是门铃在响吗？你的出租车来了，夏洛克
Isn't the doorbell working? Your taxi's here, Sherlock.
我没叫出租车，走开
I didn't order a taxi. Go away.
哦，亲爱的 他们弄得真乱
Oh, dear. They're making such a mess.
- 他们在找什么？ - 这是缉毒行动，哈德森夫人
- What are they looking for? - It's a drugs bust, Mrs Hudson.
但那些只是治疗我臀部的，是草药…
But they're just for my hip. They're herbal soothers...
闭嘴，所有人闭嘴！别动，别说话，别呼吸
Shut up, everybody shut up! Don't move, don't speak, don't breathe.
我在设法思考！安德森转过脸去，你碍到我了
I'm trying to think. Anderson, face the other way. You're putting me off.
- 什么？我的脸...  - 大家保持安静
- What? My face is - Everybody quiet and still.
- 安德森，转过背去  - 老天在上
- Anderson, turn your back. - Oh, for God's sake!
转过去，马上，拜托
Your back, now, please!
- 来吧 快思考  - 你的出租车怎么办？
- Come on, think. Quick! - What about your taxi?
哈德森夫人
Mrs Hudson!
她真聪明 聪明 没错
She was clever. Clever, yes!
她比你们都聪明，可她死了
She's cleverer than you lot and she's dead.
你们明白了吗 你们搞懂没？
Do you see? Do you get it?
她没有丢失手机，她根本没丢，她安插给他的
She didn't lose her phone, she never lost it. She planted it on him.
当她下车的时候
When she got out of the car,
她知道她要死了
she knew that she was going to her death.
她留下手机，是为了引导我们找到凶手
She left the phone in order to lead us to her killer.
- 但怎么找？  - 你说什么怎么找？
- But how? - What do you mean, how?
瑞琪儿
Rachel!
还不明白吗？瑞琪儿
Don't you see? Rachel!
瞧瞧你们，全都那么茫然
Look at you lot. You're all so vacant.
不当我是不是很好？一定很放松吧
Is it nice not being me? It must be so relaxing.
- 瑞琪儿不是人名  - 那它是什么？
- Rachel is not a name. - Then what is it?
约翰，箱子上有个名牌
John, on the luggage, there's a label.
电邮地址
E-mail address.
jennie.pink@mephone.org.uk
Er, jenny.Pink@mephone.Org.Uk.
噢，我反应太慢了，她没有笔记本电脑
Ah, I've been too slow. She didn't have a laptop,
说明她是用手机谈生意
which means she did her business on her phone.
所以是智能手机，能使用电邮
So it's a smartphone, it's e-mail enabled.
所以有个网页能登她的账户
So there was a website for her account.
用户名是她的电邮地址
The username is her e-mail address,
都齐了，现在密码是...
and all together now, the password is...?
- 瑞琪儿  - 我们能读她的邮件，那又如何？
- Rachel. - So we can read her e-mails. So what?
安德森，别说出声来
Anderson, don't talk out loud.
整条街的智商都被你拉低了
You lower the IQ of the whole street.
我们远不止能读她的电子邮件
We can do much more than just read her emails.
这是智能手机，装有GPS
It's a smartphone, it's got GPS.
意味着如果丢了，你可以在线定位它
Which means if you lose it, you can locate it online.
她把我们直接引导到杀死她的人
She's leading us directly to the man who killed her.
- 除非他扔了手机  - 我们知道他没扔
- Unless he got rid of it. - We know he didn't.
来啊，来啊，快点
Come on, come on. Quickly!
夏洛克，亲爱的，那位出租司机…
Sherlock, dear. This taxi driver...
哈德森夫人，你是不是该用晚上的那啥药了
Mrs Hudson, isn't it time for your evening soother?
准备车，弄架直升机，我们得尽快赶去
Get vehicles, get a helicopter. We have to go as fast as we can.
这个手机电池不会永远持续
This phone battery won't last for ever.
我们只有地图上的定位点，没有名字
We'll just have a map reference, not a name.
这是个开始
It's a start!
夏洛克
Sherlock...
缩小范围，不再是伦敦所有人了
Narrows it down from just anyone in London.
- 这是我们第一个适当的线索  - 夏洛克
- It's the first proper lead we've had. - Sherlock...
它在哪里？快，哪里？
Where is it? Quickly, where?
它在…这儿，它在…贝克街221B
It's...here. It's...in 22 1 Baker Street.
它怎么会在这里？
How can it be here?
怎么会？
How?
也许它在箱子里，你带回来的时候就…
Maybe it was in the case when you brought it back and it
掉到什么地方了
fell out somewhere.
而我没注意到？我？我没注意到？
And I didn't notice it? Me? I didn't notice?
不管怎样，我们发了短信，他打回电话了
Anyway, we texted him, and he called back.
伙计们，我们还要在这里找一部手机
Guys, we're also looking for a mobile somewhere here,
是死者的物品
belonged to the victim.
谁是我们不认识也会信任的人？
Who do we trust, even if we don't know them?
谁去哪里都不引人注意？
Who passes unnoticed wherever they go?
谁在人群当中狩猎？
Who hunts in the middle of a crowd?
- 夏洛克，你还好吧？  - 什么？
- Sherlock, are you OK? - What...?
对对，我没事
Yeah, yeah... I'm fine.
所以那部手机怎么会在这里？
So, how can the phone be here?
不知道
Don't know.
- 我再试试  - 好主意
- I'll try it again. - Good idea.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
新鲜空气，出去站一会儿，不会太久
Fresh air, just popping outside for a moment. Won't be long.
- 你确定没事吗？  - 我没事
- Are you sure you're all right? - I'm fine.
夏洛克·福尔摩斯叫的车
Taxi for Sherlock Holmes.
我没有叫出租
I didn't order a taxi.
不代表你不需要一辆
Doesn't mean you don't need one.
你就是那个的哥
You're the cabbie.
停在诺森伯兰街外面的那个
The one who stopped outside Northumberland Street.
是你  不是你的乘客
It was you. Not your passenger.
瞧，从来没人想过的哥
See? No-one ever thinks about the cabbie.
就像你隐形了
It's like you're invisible.
就是个后脑勺而已
Just the back of an 'ead.
连环杀手的特有优势
Proper advantage for a serial killer.
- 这是在认罪吗？  - 哦，是的
- Is this a confession? - Oh, yeah.
我另外再告诉你
I'll tell you what else...
要是你现在叫警察，我不会跑
If you call the coppers now, I won't run.
我会好好待着，他们可以拿下我，我保证
I'll sit quiet, and they can take me down, I promise.
为什么？
Why?
因为你不会那样做
Cos you're not going to do that.
我不会吗？
Am I not?
我没有杀那四个人，福尔摩斯先生
I didn't kill those four people, Mr Holmes.
我跟他们交谈
I spoke to 'em...
他们就自杀了
and they killed themselves.
如果你现在叫警察，我跟你保证一件事
If you get the coppers now, I'll promise you one thing.
我永远不会告诉你我说了什么
I will never tell you what I said.
但也再不会有人死了
No-one else will die, though,
我相信他们接受这结果
and I believe they call that a result.
而你将永远不会明白那些人怎么死的
And you won't ever understand how those people died.
你关心的是哪种结果呢？
What kind of result do you care about?
要是我想要了解
If I wanted to understand...
我该怎么做？
...what would I do?
让我载你一程
Let me take you for a ride.
让你也把我杀了？
So you can kill me too?
我不想杀你，福尔摩斯先生
I don't want to kill you, Mr Holmes.
我会跟你谈谈
I'm going to talk to you...
然后你就会杀死自己
...and then you're going to kill yourself.
他刚上了一辆出租车
He just got in a cab...
是夏洛克，他刚坐出租车走了
It's Sherlock. He just drove off in a cab.
我跟你说过，他常这样
I told you, he does that.
又特么走了
He bloody left again.
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting our time!
我在打那个手机，铃声在响
I'm...calling the phone, it's ringing out.
既然响铃，它就不在这里
And if it's ringing, it's not here.
我再试试搜索
I'll try the search again.
这还重要吗？有半点用吗
Does it matter? Does any of it?
他就是个疯子 他总是让你失望
He's just a lunatic and he'll always let you down.
你在浪费时间 我们大家的时间
And you're wasting your time. All our time.
好了，大家
OK, everybody...
收工
done here.
你怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
我认出了你
Oh, I recognised you.
就在我看见你追踪我的车时
Soon as I saw you chasing my cab.
夏洛克·福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes!
有人跟我警告过你
I was warned about you.
我也去过你的网站，精彩的东西，爱死了
I've been on your website too. Brilliant stuff! Loved it.
谁跟你警告过我？
Who warned you about me?
只是一个注意你的人
Just someone out there who's noticed.
谁？
Who?
谁会注意我？
Who would notice me?
- 你太谦虚了，福尔摩斯先生  - 我真不是
- You're too modest, Mr Holmes. - I'm really not.
你有个粉丝呢
Got yourself a fan.
多告诉我一点
Tell me more.
你只能知道这么多了
That's all you're going to know.
这辈子里
In this lifetime.
他为什么那么做？他为什么必须走？
Why did he do that? Why did he have to leave?
你比我更了解他
You know him better than I do.
我认识他五年了  但还是不了解他
I've known him for five years and, no, I don't.
那你为何容忍他？
So why do you put up with him?
因为我绝望没招了，这就是原因
Because I'm desperate, that's why.
也因为夏洛克·福尔摩斯是个了不起的人
And because Sherlock Holmes is a great man,
而且我想，有一天，如果我们非常非常幸运的话
and I think one day, if we're very, very lucky,
他甚至可能成为个好人
he might even be a good one.
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
你知道伦敦的每一条街道  你很清楚我们在哪里
You know every street in London. You know exactly where we are.
罗兰克尔成人教育学院
Roland-Kerr Further Education College.
- 为什么来这儿？  - 这儿开着
- Why here? - It's open.
清洁工在里面
Cleaners are in.
当的哥有一个好处…
One thing about being a cabbie -
你总是知道某个僻静理想的杀人地点
you always know a nice quiet spot for a murder.
我惊讶我们没有更多人拓展这业务
I'm surprised more of us don't branch out.
你就跟受害者走进去？怎么办到？
And you just walk your victims in? How?
哦…乏味
Oh... Dull.
别担心，好戏在后头呢
Don't worry. It gets better.
你不能用枪逼着人自杀吧
You can't make people take their own lives at gunpoint.
我没有
I don't.
比那个强多了
It's much better than that.
对你不用这个，因为你会跟来
Don't need this with you. Cos you'll follow me.
你看如何？
Well, what do you think?
随你喜欢了
It's up to you.
你是要死在这里的人
You're the one who's going to die here.
不，我不是
No, I'm not.
他们都这么说
That's what they all say.
咱俩聊聊吧？
Shall we talk?
有点冒险，对吗
Bit risky, wasn't it?
从半打警察眼皮子底下把我带走
Took me away under the eye of about half a dozen policemen.
他们没那么蠢
They're not that stupid.
而且哈德森太太会记得你
And Mrs Hudson will remember you.
你把这叫做冒险？  不...
You call that a risk? Nah...
这才叫冒险
This...is a risk.
哦，我喜欢这一点
Oh, I like this bit.
因为你还没搞懂，对吧
Cos you don't get it yet, do ya?
你马上就会明白
But you're about to.
我只需这样…
I just have to do this...
没想到这个，对吧
Weren't expecting that, were ya?
你会喜欢这个的
Oh, you're gonna love this.
- 喜欢什么？  - 夏洛克·福尔摩斯，看看你
- Love what? - Sherlock Holmes...look at you!
活生生的在这里
Here in the flesh.
你那个网站，你的粉丝给我讲了
That website of yours, your fan told me about it.
我的粉丝？
My fan?
你那么杰出
You are brilliant.
你是个特有的天才
You are a proper genius.
演绎科学，那东西...
The Science Of Deduction. Now, that...
是特出的想法
is proper thinking.
我们就来说说，人们为什么不会思考？
Between you and me sitting here, why can't people think?
这不让你发疯吗？
Don't it make you mad?
为什么人们就不能思考一下呢
Why can't people just think?
哦，我明白了，这么说你也是个特有的天才
Oh, I see... So you're a proper genius too.
看起来不像吧
Don't look it, do I?
可笑的小男人，开着出租
Funny little man driving a cab.
不过你马上就能了解更多了
But you'll know better in a minute.
很大机会 这是你一生所知的最后一件事
Chances are it'll be the last thing you ever know.
好吧，两个瓶子，解释下
OK, two bottles. Explain.
一个无毒瓶  一个有毒瓶
There's a good bottle and a bad bottle.
你拿了无毒瓶里的药丸，你活
You take the pill from the good bottle, you live.
你拿了有毒瓶里的药丸...你死
You take the pill from the bad bottle...you die.
- 两个瓶子当然完全一样  - 各个方面
- Both bottles are of course identical. - In every way.
- 但你知道哪个是哪个  - 我当然知道
- And you know which is which. - Of course I know.
而我不知道
But I don't.
你知道就不是游戏了  是你来选
Wouldn't be a game if you knew - you're the one who chooses.
我为什么要选？我什么也得不到
Why should I? I've got nothing to go on.
我有什么好处？
What's in it for me?
我还没告诉你最精彩的部分呢
I haven't told you the best bit yet.
不管你选哪个瓶子
Whatever bottle you choose,
我将拿起另一瓶里的药丸
I take the pill from the other one.
然后  我们一起...
And then together...
把我们的药吃下去
we take our medicine.
我不作弊，由你来选
I won't cheat. It's your choice.
你选剩下哪个药丸我都吃掉
I'll take whatever pill you don't.
没想到这一手，是吧，福尔摩斯先生？
Didn't expect that, did you, Mr Holmes?
这就是你对其他人的做法
This is what you did to the rest of them,
- 你给他们一个选择？ - 现在我给你一个
- you gave them a choice? - And now I'm giving you one.
你不用着急
You take your time.
集中精神
Get yourself together.
我要你尽情游戏
I want your best game.
这不是游戏，这是机率
It's not a game, it's chance.
我玩了4次，我还活着
I've played four times. I'm alive.
这不是机率，福尔摩斯先生，这是下棋
It's not chance, Mr Holmes - it's chess.
这是一局棋，只走一步
It's a game of chess, with one move...
一个幸存者
...and one survivor.
而这…这个…
And this...this...
就是那一步
is the move.
我刚给你的是无毒的 还是有毒的瓶子？
Did I just give you the good bottle or the bad bottle?
你可以选任何一个
You can choose either one.
不，雷斯垂德探长，我得和他谈谈
No, Detective Inspector Lestrade - I need to speak to him.
很重要，紧急状况
It's important. It's an emergency.
呃，这里左转，请你左转
Er, left here, please. Left here...
你准备好了吗，福尔摩斯先生？
You ready yet, Mr Holmes?
准备好下棋了吗？
Ready to play?
下什么？ 这是50比50的机率
Play what? It's a 50:50 chance.
你不是和数字下，而是和我下
You're not playing the numbers - you're playing me.
我刚才给你无毒药丸还是有毒药丸呢
Did I just give you the good pill or the bad pill?
这是诈唬呢？
Is it a bluff
还是双重诈唬？
or a double bluff?
还是三重诈唬？
Or a triple bluff?
仍然不过是机率
It's still just chance.
连赢四个人？ 这不是机率
Four people, in a row? It's not chance.
- 运气  - 是天赋
- Luck. - It's genius!
我知道人们怎么思考
I know how people think.
我知道人们怎么考虑我的想法
I know how people think I think.
我能全看透，就像脑子里有一张地图
I can see it all like a map inside my head.
人人都那么蠢，连你也是
Everyone's so stupid, even you.
或者，也许上帝就是偏爱我
Or maybe God just loves me.
不管怎样，你是个浪费生命的的哥
Either way, you're wasted as a cabbie.
所以….
So...
你四次冒生命危险，只为杀死陌生人，为什么？
...you risked your life four times just to kill strangers - why?
该下棋了
Time to play.
我正在下呢，该我走棋了
Oh, I am playing. This is my turn.
你的左耳后面有剃须膏沫
There's shaving foam behind your left ear.
没人给你指出来
Nobody's pointed it out to you.
痕迹说明以前也有过
Traces of where it's happened before,
所以明显你是一个人住，没人告诉你
so obviously you live on your own there's no-one to tell you.
但还有一张孩子们的照片
But there's a photograph of children.
孩子们的母亲却从照片里裁掉了
The children's mother's been cut out of the picture
如果她死了，那还会留在里面
If she'd died, she'd still be there.
照片是旧的，但相框很新
The photograph's old, but the frame's new.
你想念你的孩子们，却无法见到他们
You think of your children, but you don't get to see them.
分居的父亲
Estranged father.
她带走了孩子
She took the kids,
但你仍然爱他们，仍然心痛
but you still love them, and it still hurts.
哦，还有呢
Ah, but there's more.
你的衣服，最近才洗过
Your clothes. Recently laundered,
但你穿的每一样东西，至少有3年那么旧
but everything you're wearing is at least...three years old?
保留现状 但对前途无计划
Keeping up appearances, but not planning ahead.
而你又在这里搞神风谋杀，这是为何？
And here you are on a kamikaze murder spree. What's that about?
哦，三年前…他们是那时候告诉你的吧？
three years ago. Is that when they told you?
告诉我什么？
Told me what?
- 说你是将死之人  - 你也是
- That you're a dead man walking. - So are you.
反正你时日不多了，我说得对吗？
You don't have long, though. Am I right?
动脉瘤  就在这里面
Aneurism. Right in 'ere.
任何一口气都可能是我最后一口
Any breath could be my last.
就因为你要死了，你就连杀四个人
And because you're dying, you've just murdered four people.
我可比那四个人活得久
I've outlived four people.
对于得动脉瘤的人，那可是最高兴的事了
That's the most fun you can have with an aneurism.
不...不 还有别的
No... No, there's something else.
你不会因为痛苦而杀四个人
You didn't just kill four people because you're bitter.
痛苦是一种麻痹
Bitterness is a paralytic.
爱才是更为歹毒的动力
Love is a much more vicious motivator.
这和你的孩子有某种关联
Somehow, this is about your children.
- 你厉害  - 但怎么关联呢
- You are good, in't ya? - But how?
等我死了，他们得不到多少，我的孩子们
When I die, they won't get much, my kids.
开出租车赚不了多少钱
Not a lot of money in driving cabs.
连环杀人也没有
Or serial killing.
你会吃惊的
You'd be surprised.
那就惊惊我
Surprise me.
我有个赞助商
I have a sponsor.
你有什么？
You have a what?
我每取一条命，就有一笔钱给我的孩子
For every life I take, money goes to my kids.
我杀得越多…他们就越宽裕
The more I kill... the better off they'll be.
看吧  比你想象的好得多
You see? It's nicer than you think.
有谁会赞助一个连环杀手？
Who'd sponsor a serial killer?
谁会是夏洛克·福尔摩斯的粉丝？
Who'd be a fan of Sherlock Holmes?
你不是唯一欣赏高明谋杀的人
You're not the only one to enjoy a good murder.
外面还有一些人 跟你一样
There's others out there just like you,
不过你只是一介凡人
except you're just a man.
而他们却远不止如此
And they're so much more than that.
什么意思…
What do you mean...
不止是一个人？
more than a man?
一个组织…什么？
An organisation...what?
有一个名字，没人说出来
There's a name that no-one says.
我也不会说的
And I'm not going to say it either.
现在，闲聊够了
Now, enough chatter.
该选择了
Time to choose.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
要是我两个都不选呢？我可以直接走人
What if I don't choose either? I could just walk out of here.
你可以选50%的机会
You can take a 50:50 chance,
或让我射爆你的头
or I can shoot you in the head.
够好笑的
Funnily enough,
至今没人选这个选项
no-one's ever gone for that option.
那我选枪 请吧
I'll have the gun, please.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
肯定的  就选枪
Definitely. The gun.
你不想给朋友打个电话？
You don't want to phone a friend
选枪
The gun.
看见真枪我认得出来
I know a real gun when I see one.
- 其他人都没发现  - 无疑
- None of the others did. - Clearly.
好了，这一切非常有趣
Well, this has been very interesting.
期待法庭上见
I look forward to the court case.
你走之前，问一下你想清楚了吗？
Just before you go, did you figure it out?
哪一瓶是无毒的？
Which one's the good bottle?
当然，小孩把戏
Course. Child's play.
那是哪一个呢？
Well, which one, then?
你会挑哪个呢？
Which one would you have picked?
我只想知道自己能否打败你
Just so I know whether I could have beaten you.
来吧
Come on!
开始游戏吧
Play the game.
有意思
Oh! Interesting.
你怎么想？
So what do you think?
来吧？
Shall we?
真的  你怎么想的？
Really...what do you think?
你能打败我吗？
Can you beat me?
你是否够聪明
Are you clever enough...
可以赌上性命？
to bet your life?
夏洛克
Sherlock!
我打赌你很无聊  不是吗
I bet you get bored, don't you?
我知道你无聊
I know you do.
你这样的人 如此聪明
A man like you. So clever.
但若不能证明，聪明又有何意义呢？
But what's the point of being clever if you can't prove it?
仍旧是瘾君子
Still the addict.
但这个 这才是真正让你上瘾的东西
But this...this is what you're really addicted to.
你定会竭尽全力
You'll do anything...
全力以赴，避免无聊
...anything at all, to stop being bored.
你现在不无聊了，对吧？
You're not bored now, are ya?
这不错吧
Isn't it good?
我对了吗？
Was I right?
我对了，是吧？
I was, wasn't I?
我刚才挑对了吗？
Did I get it right?
好吧  那就告诉我
OK...tell me this.
你的赞助者，他是谁？
Your sponsor. Who was it?
那个跟你提起我的人  我的粉丝
The one who told you about me, my fan.
我要名字
I want a name.
不
No...
你要死了，但还有时间折磨你
You're dying, but there's still time to hurt you.
给我…名字
Give me...A name.
名字  快说
A name! Now!
名字
The name!
莫里亚蒂
Moriarty!
为什么给我毛毯？
Why have I got this blanket?
他们老是给我披这条毛毯
They keep putting this blanket on me.
- 对，为防你受惊吓  - 我没有受惊
- Yeah, it's for shock. - I'm not in shock.
对，但有人要拍照片
Yeah, but some of the guys want to take photographs.
那个枪手，没有迹象吗？
So, the shooter - no sign?
我们赶到前就消失了
Cleared off before we got here.
不过我料想那种人会有很多敌人
But a guy like that would have had enemies, I suppose.
其中有人可能正在追杀他 不过
One of them could have been following him, but...
我们现在毫无头绪
we've got nothing to go on.
哦，我可不这么想
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
那好，告诉我
OK. Give me.
他们从墙上挖出的子弹，来自手枪
The bullet they just dug out of the wall's from a handgun.
那种距离外的致命一击，从那种武器发射
A kill shot over that distance, from that kind of a weapon,
那一枪很出色，你们要找的不单是个神枪手，是个战士
that's a crack shot. You're looking for not just a marksman, a fighter.
他的手必须纹丝不动
His hands couldn't have shaken at all,
所以很清楚他习惯于暴力
so clearly he's acclimatised to violence.
然而他等到我面临直接危险才开火
He didn't fire until I was in immediate danger, though
很强的道德原则
so strong moral principle.
你找的这人
You're looking for a man
或许有军队服役的历史 以及...
probably with a history of military service and...
钢铁般的神经
nerves of steel...
其实 你猜怎么？ 别管我说的
Actually, do you know what? Ignore me.
- 啥？  - 别管那些话
- Sorry? - Ignore all of that.
- 那只是…受惊后的胡说  - 你去哪儿？
- It's just the, er...the shock talking. - Where are you going?
我得去聊聊租金
I just need to...talk about the...the rent.
- 我还有几个问题呢  - 现在吗  我受惊了
- I've still got questions. - Oh, what now?! I'm in shock
你看，我披着毛毯呢
look, I've got a blanket.
- 夏洛克  - 而且
- Sherlock! - And...
我刚帮你抓了连环杀手
I just caught you a serial killer...
多多少少吧
more or less.
好吧，我们明天找你，你走吧
OK. We'll pull you in tomorrow. Off you go.
嗯，多诺万警佐，刚才解释了…
Erm...Sergeant Donovan's...just been explaining...
所有事情，两颗药丸…
everything. Two pills...
吓人的事，对吧？ 吓人
Dreadful business, isn't it? Dreadful.
好枪法
Good shot.
对对，一定是的，穿过窗户
Yes. Yes, must have been. Through that window.
你清楚
Well, you'd know.
得把你手指上的火药灼痕去掉
Need to get the powder burns out of your fingers.
我认为你不会因此坐牢
I don't suppose you'd serve time for this,
但我们还是避免上庭吧
but let's avoid the court case.
- 你没事吧  - 对，我当然没事
- Are you all right? - Yes, of course I'm all right.
- 你刚杀了人  - 是的，我...
- Well, you have just killed a man. - Yes, I...
那倒是，对吧
That's true, isn't it?
不过他不是个很好的人
But he wasn't a very nice man.
是呀，他真不算好人，不是吗
No. No, he wasn't, really, was he?
说白了就是个坏透了的的哥
Frankly, a bloody awful cabbie.
那倒是，他是个坏的哥
That's true, he was a bad cabbie.
你该看看他带我们兜了多少路到这里
You should have seen the route he took us to get here.
别闹，我们不能笑 这是罪案现场，别闹
Stop! We can't giggle, it's a crime scene. Stop it.
- 是你开的枪  - 你声音小点
- You're the one who shot him. - Keep your voice down!
- 抱歉  他是太紧张了  - 抱歉
- Sorry, it's just, erm...nerves, I think. - Sorry.
你不会真要吞那该死的药片，对吧？
You were going to take that damn pill, weren't you?
当然不会
Course I wasn't.
拖延时间而已，知道你会出现
Biding my time. Knew you'd turn up.
不，你不知道
No, you didn't.
你就是这么找刺激的，对吧
That's how you get your kicks, isn't it?
冒生命危险证明自己聪明
You risk your life to prove you're clever.
我干嘛这么做？
Why would I do that?
因为你是个笨蛋
Because you're an idiot.
- 晚饭？  - 饿死了
- Dinner? - Starving.
贝克街尽头，有家不错的中餐馆，开到凌晨两点
End of Baker Street, there's a good Chinese. Stays open till two.
中餐馆的好坏能从门把底部三分之一看出来
You can tell a good Chinese by the bottom third of the door handle.
夏洛克，是他，我跟你提过的那个人
Sherlock...that's him, that's the man I was talking to you about.
我很清楚他是谁
I know exactly who that is.
好啊…又破了一个案件？
So...another case cracked.
多么热心公益呀
How very public-spirited.
虽然那不是你真实的动机，对吧
Though that's never really your motivation, is it?
你来这里干嘛？
What are you doing here?
一如既往，我关心你
As ever, I'm concerned about you.
对，我已经听到你的“关心”了
Yes, I've been hearing about your "Concern".
总是如此咄咄逼人
Always so aggressive.
你从没想过你我是一边的吗？
Did it never occur to you that you and I belong on the same side?
说来奇怪…没有
Oddly enough...no.
我们的共同点比你愿意相信的要多
We have more in common than you'd like to believe.
咱们之间的这点不和 只不过是孩子气
This petty feud between us is simply childish.
有人会因此难受
People will suffer.
你知道这总是让老妈烦心
And you know how it always upset Mummy.
我让她烦心？
I upset her?
我？
Me?
让她烦心的不是我，麦克罗夫特
It wasn't me that upset her, Mycroft.
不 不  等等
No. No, wait...
老妈？谁的老妈？
Mummy? Who's Mummy?
母亲，我们的母亲
Mother. Our mother.
这是我哥哥，麦克罗夫特
This is my brother, Mycroft.
又发福了
Putting on weight again?
- 实际上，减肥了  - 他是你哥？
- Losing it, in fact. - He's your brother?
当然是我哥
Course he's my brother.
- 那他不是…  - 不是什么？
- So he's not... - Not what?
不知道…犯罪主脑？
I don't know...criminal mastermind?
也差不多
Close enough.
老天爷呀
For goodness' sake,
我在英国政府里官居末职
I occupy a minor position in the British Government.
他就是英国政府
He is the British Government,
当他不忙于英国秘密机构或中情局的副业时
when he's not too busy being the British Secret Service or the CIA on a freelance basis.
晚安，麦克罗夫特
Good evening, Mycroft.
尽量别在我到家之前发动一场战争
Try not to start a war before I get home
你知道那对交通有何影响的
you know what it does for the traffic.
所以，你说关心他的时候
So, when you say you're concerned about him,
你是真的关心他？
you actually are concerned?
是啊，当然
Yes, of course.
真是小孩子的不和吗？
It actually is a childish feud?
他一向如此愤愤不平
He's always been so resentful.
你可以想象圣诞晚餐的情形
You can imagine the Christmas dinners.
是啊
Yeah
不，天，不能
No... God, no.
我最好还是…又见面了
I'd better, erm... Hello again.
- 你好  - 我们今晚早些时候见过
- Hello. - We met earlier on this evening.
- 那好，晚安  - 晚安，华生医生
- OK. Good night. - Good night, Dr Watson.
走  吃点心去
So, dim sum.Mmm!
我总能猜到幸运饼写什么
I can always predict the fortune cookies.
- 不，不可能  - 差不多
- No, you can't. - Almost can.
不过你真中过枪
You did get shot, though.
- 什么？  - 在阿富汗  真的受过枪伤
- Sorry? - In Afghanistan. There was an actual wound.
- 哦对，肩膀上  - 肩膀，我就知道
- Oh. Yeah, shoulder. - Shoulder! I thought so.
- 不你不知道  - 左肩
- No, you didn't. - The left one.
- 瞎猜中的  - 我从不瞎猜
- Lucky guess. - I never guess.
你就是猜的
Yes, you do.
- 你干嘛这么乐？  - 莫里亚蒂
- What are you so happy about? - Moriarty.
- 莫里亚蒂是什么？  - 一无所知
- What's Moriarty? - I've absolutely no idea.
长官，可以走了吗？
Sir, shall we go?
有意思，那个当兵的
Interesting, that soldier fellow.
他可能造就我弟弟
He could be the making of my brother...
也可能让他更加无可救药
or make him worse than ever.
无论哪种，我们最好提高他们的监控级别
Either way, we'd better upgrade their surveillance status.
启动三级预案
Grade 3 active.
抱歉长官，对谁的监控级别？
Sorry, sir - whose status?
夏洛克·福尔摩斯，还有华生医生
Sherlock Holmes and Dr Watson.